# **MD Farhad Jaman**

## FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

#### Social Info

- nttps://devfarhad.vercel.app
- in https://linkedin.com/in/farhadjaman
- https://github.com/farhadjaman

Skills: VueJS, MERN Stack, Tailwind CSS, Framer motion, Redux, Firebase, Docker, GraphQL, Type-

#### **About Me**

2 years of experience in VueJS. Former Web Developer Intern at Selise Digital Platforms Ltd. Currently employed as a Software Engineer at startups Afilo and Growth and Analytics. Specializes in MERN stack development. Likes to automate stuff and travel. Fascinated with both kinds of cloud.

# **Work Experience**

#### Software Engineer, Growth & Analytics

April 2023- ongoing

- -Designed and developed a seamless landing page for a growth and analytics company using VueJS, NextJS, Tailwind CSS, and Framer Motion. Also created campaigns and products to boost business growth.
- -Handled various projects as an integration engineer to integrate analytics tools like Google Analytics, Segment, and Mixpanel into client websites.

## Software Engineer, Afilo

August 2023- ongoing

- -ReactJS, Tailwind CSS, and Redux specialist with experience leading the design and development of complex web applications.
- -Created various UI features and authentication in Marchant page

#### Software Engineer Intern, Selise Digital Platforms

Feb 2023- ongoing

- -Expertise in synchronous and asynchronous JavaScript, MongoDB, Express.js, and Docker for streamlined web development and deployment. Proven ability to configure and manage VPS, Nginx, and other infrastructure services.
- -Gained exposure to office culture and regular Scrum meetings.

## **Projects**

#### Personal Porfolio Website

Designed and developed a portfolio website using Next.js, TailwindCSS, and Framer Motion, showcasing my skills and projects in a visually engaging and user-friendly manner.

Live: https://devfarhad.ninja

### Ecommerce Project -1

Teamed up to develop Afilo's landing page and authentication system. Currently enhancing the merchant user interface with Tailwind CSS and Redux.

Live: https://afilo.io

## Ecommerce Project -2

Designed and built a full-stack website with custom CMS using NextJS, NodeJS, and MongoDB for efficient content management and enhanced functionality.

Live: https://watchmans.vercel.app

#### Angular Project during Internship

Developed an Angular 11+ frontend and Node is backend for a cloud-deployed project using MongoDB. Leveraged Angular Material for UI design and RxJS for component communication.

Github: https://github.com/farhadjaman/escapedfoodclient Live: https://escapedflavors.vercel.app/

# **Education & Additional Experience**

IUPC BUP 2nd Runners-up

400+ Questions across different competitive Programming Platforms

ACM ICPC Dhaka Regional Preliminary Contest 2020-2023

 BSc in Information & Communication Engineering, Bangladesh University of Professionals, Jan 2020 - Dec 2023 3.66/4.00 CGPA (2023)